Both
Type 1
Type 2
These two types are often easy to tell apart, unless someone is differentiating between wing types. Both serious, conscience-driven, of service, can be very altruistic. 
Appeals to principles over personal feelings
Highly personal
“”
Defend autonomy
Seek close connection
“”
Restrained in expression of positive feelings, but easier to express negative feelings
Unrestrained in positive feelings, but more difficult to express negative feelings



Both
Type 1
Type 3
Both efficient and highly organized, but...
Idealists, striving for perfection. Efficient for the sake of reaching the desired standard.
Pragmatic, driven by goals. Efficient for the sake of just getting it done.

“”
Attached to methods or procedures.
More adaptable to get desired result.
Both put feelings aside for the sake of efficiency, becoming cool and impersonal but…
Less able to conceal irritations and disappointments.
More able to mask what is bothering them.
“”
Able to suppress feelings for the time being.
Detachment of feelings.

“Listen to me—I know the right way to do things.” Offers themselves as examples of high standard.
“Be like me—I have got it together. Offers themselves as exemplars of individual perfection.


Both
Type 1
Type 4
These two types are often easy to tell apart. They might seem similar if focusing mostly on the negative aspects: perfectionistic, dissatisfied, frustrated, perceived as fussy or picky.
Attend to responsibilities first, feelings later. Would not allow self to “indulge” in feelings very long.
Want to sort out feelings first, deal with duties after. Might not be able to mobilize self to meet responsibilities.
Both critical and picky, but…
Critical over others’ inefficiency or failures.
Critical over others’ lack of awareness of sensitivities.

Respond by pushing other party harder.
Respond by withdrawing.
Both are related because…
This type, when stressed, looks like an unhealthy Type B—moody and irrational.
This type, when growing, looks like a healthy Type A—more objective and principled.



Both
Type 1
Type 5
Can both be considered deep thinking types, but…
More from the gut. Emphasis on certainty and judgment.
More from the mind. Relative lack of certainty and difficulty with discernment.

More interested in using thoughts to relate more perfectly to themselves and the world.
More interested in how ideas relate to other thoughts that arise in the mind.

Judge from idealistic standards.
Constantly investigating and questioning assumptions.


Both
Type 1
Type 6
Both are compliant types (“should” or “must”), but…
Compliant to demands of ideals.
Compliant to demands of other people.

“Inner Critic” in the head.
“Inner Committee” in the head.
Both may feel guilty, but…
Guilty when doing something contrary to ideals.
Guilty when doing something contrary to the commitments to allies, beliefs, and authorities.
^ These two types are often easy to tell apart.
Self-controlled, impersonal efficiency, orderliness, propriety.
Anxious, indecisive, ambivalent, reactive.


Both
Type 1
Type 7
Both are related because…
This type, when growing, looks like a healthy Type A—spontaneous and joyful.
This type, when stressed, looks like an unhealthy Type A—perfectionistic and critical.
Both share idealism and a sense of “mission,” holding high ideals, but…
Hold high standards and expect to be disappointed.
Usually very optimistic about the future.

Know their mission.
“Feel” their mission.
Both might express “perfectionism”, but…
Perfectionism drives them to be angry and critique themselves.
“Perfectionism” drives them to become frustrated because of failed expectations (the optimistic outcome did not occur).
Still, there exist a number of differences.
Rigid in plans, often focused. Quite self-conscious socially. Driven by anger.
Spontaneous in plans, sometimes scattered. Unselfconscious socially. Driven by anxiety.


Both
Type 1
Type 8
Both have strong wills and action-oriented, but…
This type tries to convince others to do the right thing from a moral standpoint.
This type tries to convince using personal convictions and own self-confidence.
Both are involved with justice, but…
View justice as an extremely important value to restore humans to a certain standard.
View justice with more of a visceral response, rushing in to protect others.
Both may have aggressive impulses, but…
This type is more compliant to their ideals.
This type is more given over to their gut response.


Both
Type 1
Type 9
These two types may be confusing if someone is differentiating between wing types. This could be difficult. Both can be idealistic, philosophical, and somewhat withdrawn, but…
When facing conflict, the principle is foremost and will drive home their point, even if it causes arguments.
When facing conflict, even if this type may hold strong personal convictions, they generally do not want to start arguments.

More driven, having difficulty taking a break.
Enjoy down time, easily able to take a break.

When handling stress, at first try harder, but then may end up being moody.
When handling stress, become disengaged and resistant, but then may end up being anxious and reactive.


Both
Type 2
Type 3
These two types may be confusing if someone is differentiating between wing types. Both lean into the desire to be liked and please others, but…
This type attempts to get others to like them by doing good things for them, focusing on the other person.
This type attempts to get others to like them by developing excellence, thus gaining attention.

Openly sentimental and emote easily.
More composed and have difficulty accessing feelings.
Both may seem ambitious, but…

Feel uncomfortable going after goals directly, feeling it would be too selfish.
Are very goal-driven.
^^
Overexert themselves and lose patience, blowing up.
Overexert themselves and burn out, becoming detached and passive.


Both
Type 2
Type 4
Both are feeling, sensitive types. Both (and really, all types) can be depressed. They put great emphasis on the ups and downs of relationships, but…
This type tends to move toward others and engage them.
This type tends to withdraw from others, hoping that others will seek them out.

Looks for people to rescue.
Looks for someone to rescue them.

Aware of others’ feelings, but unaware of own needs.
Highly aware of own emotional state, but may not recognize impact on others.


Both
Type 2
Type 5
These two types are very easy to tell apart. Both may feel rejected easily, but…
This type is emotionally expressive and highly people-oriented.
This type is emotionally detached and can be known as loners.

Copes by winning people over.
Copes by detaching from hurt and isolating self.

Go by feelings.
Go by intellectual concepts.


Both
Type 2
Type 6
Both are warm and engaging, wanting to be liked, but…
This type wants to be loved and be important to others.
This type wants to have the approval and support of others.
Both ingratiate themselves with people, but…
Try to win favor by operating out of warmth and friendliness, offering their love and friendship.
Try to win favor by being playful and silly to elicit emotional response.
Both types are emotional, but…
“Throw out net of feelings” to see whom they can sweep into their lives.
Warily invite selected people into their lives.

Want to be close with others.
Want to create partnerships with others that will support them—but not too close.

Openly warm and demonstrative about how they feel toward others.
Ambivalent about feelings, often anxious.


Both
Type 2
Type 7
Both can be emotional and histrionic, but…
Deeply feeling, with emotions changing less.
Quicker, more fickle emotions.

More low-key than Type B.
Actively emote high highs and low lows, but these ups and downs do not last long.
Both are gregarious and enjoy being with people, but…
More interpersonal, genuinely friendly, warm, and interested in others.
Do not get as involved in people’s lives, but like to float around people to bring more enjoyment.

Desire to be important.
Desire to have a good time with people around.

Want others to need them.
Do not want to be needed by others—have little patience for anyone who is too dependent on them.

Possessive of their friends due to high investment.
Tend to be less attached to people, not as clingy.
These two types are often confused, but…
Like to indulge in sharing feelings and intimacies.
Like to indulge in filling minds with interesting possibilities and concepts.



Both
Type 2
Type 8
Both may dominate others, but…
Do so indirectly, often disguised as concern for others.
Do so directly, making it clear that there is a power struggle.

Difficulty communicating anger, even though they may be very upset with someone, resorting to indirect approaches.
Openly aggressive, very direct in communication.
Both struggle with rejection, but…

This type tends to handle conflict with covert neediness and manipulation.
This type tends to handle conflict with intense passions in interpersonal conflicts.
Both are related because…
This type, when stressed, looks like an unhealthy Type B—aggressive and dominating.
This type, when growing, looks like a healthy Type A—open-hearted and caring.



Both
Type 3
Type 4
These two types may be confusing if someone is differentiating between wing types. But…
Tend to focus on task, on efficiency, on performance, pushing aside feelings.
Want to accomplish things too, but when difficult feelings arise, they want to stop and process before returning to tasks.

Might be seen from the other type as inauthentic.
Might be seen from the other type as unprofessional.









